Change history? Oh boy.
Yes, I want you to prove whether or not it can be done.
I'm curious to know if this unsalvageable ruin, this tragedy devoid of all hope, could possibly be prevented if we tried.
So you think there might be a chance? I mean, I've always heard it said that history will correct itself, but...
Sure, but do the people who say that typically have the power to put their money where their mouth is?
Well, no, I guess not.
Doesn't matter how crowded this world may get. The only one around who can interfere with time is me. And don't you forget it.
A little pointer, though. Remember that whatever you see before you is real. And whatever moment you're in is the only truth there is, so be present.
Will I really be able to save Origami?
Hard to say. That really depends on you.
All right. I'm in. Let's do it.
Would you care to explain what you're doing?
Cutting through this way will be a lot faster.
Who the heck are you?
Um, sorry. Gotta go!
Hey! You get back here!
Shido?
Shoot! I can't afford to waste time like this!
But now, what do I do?
Shido?
Yep, just me.
Have you seen anyone sketchy come through here?
Uh, no, I haven't seen anybody.
Really?
That's weird.
Is it?
Huh.
Oh, never mind. Don't you worry about it.
Tell your mom hi for me, okay?
Oh, that was a close one.
Good thinking. I'm impressed.
Yeah.
Never would have imagined that I'd used Natsumi's transformation powers, but they came in super handy.
I'll say they did.
Looking like that, no one will bat an eye seeing you in the past.
Yeah, sure. But how do I get back to normal?
Oh, you're so cute. Why would you bother?
Yeah, very funny.
That must be Coterie.
So it would seem.
Let's go!
A girl defies time and transforms into a devil, while a solitary boy goes up against an impending disaster.
Oh, he says it.
A girl defies time and strumming la peatzie in the future.
Oh, he's my sister.
What does that make up against an impending disaster?
Oh, I don't caver.
I don't know.
It sucks.
Alright, let's go!
Let's revive what did you do here.
Keep it up and breathe back.
Send me what to the fresh air, okay?
I know it doesn't.
I'll see you next time.
She can't hear me!
Origami!
Come on!
Mom and Dad, there you are.
Shido?
Don't worry, I'm fine.
But did they...
Wait.
No!
You did this!
I'll never forgive you!
Never!
I'll kill you!
I swear I will!
Someday, I'll kill you!
I don't believe it.
What the hell's going on?
This is insane!
Not really.
For someone like Origami to have ended up in her current state,
I knew for a fact something significant had to have happened.
She's gone!
Yujbat must have reached its limit.
She went back to her original time.
No way.
So I guess this means Origami wasn't able to change history after all.
This is terrible.
Hey, Origami!
Watch out!
Sorry to knock you down.
Are you okay?
They're gone now.
They're both gone.
I don't...
Origami...
Sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Who are you?
It's all right.
It's gonna be all right.
Listen to me.
Someday you'll understand.
I promise.
All of this.
The truth.
But please don't forget.
You are never alone, okay?
I'm not.
What?
All of your sadness and your hate!
Let me carry all of it for you!
If you're lost, I'll find you!
When something happens and it's too much, please come to me!
Give it all to me!
Everything!
It's okay!
I'll take all of it!
Do you hear me?
Okay?
Don't let despair take you over, Origami!
Thanks.
You're very kind.
But who exactly are you anyway?
Uh, oh, I'm, uh, my name is Shido Itsuka.
I just live in the neighborhood.
Shido Itsuka.
Did you really mean everything you just said?
Yeah, of course. I meant every word.
Okay.
Well then, this will be the last time I ever cry.
But it's also the last time I'll smile.
What?
All my sadness and my joy, all the fun in my life.
I give to you.
But this anger, this anger is mine alone.
I'm going to kill that thing, that angel.
No matter what it takes, no matter how long it takes.
Origami, wait.
So sure, you can carry everything for me, till I'm ready to kill the angel.
Until then.
So that's what happened.
What an ironic turn of events.
How unexpected.
This is disappointing.
I'm sorry.
You used Yudbed, and I still couldn't do anything to fix this.
No, that's not what I'm talking about.
What?
Shida, we just learned Origami's the one who killed her parents.
And that means, this whole situation wouldn't have happened if not for my Zath-Kil.
So I have to be honest.
That's more than a little upsetting to me.
Hold on.
I think you're being a little unfair to yourself, don't you?
I mean, you didn't want this to happen.
No, of course not.
Anyway, it doesn't matter because it's all over now.
Is that really what you think?
It's true.
As far as that world is concerned, what's done is done.
Full stop.
However, I just happened to be presented with a new method to fix this mess only a moment ago.
What are you talking about presented?
By who?
Believe it or not, by you a few dozen minutes from now.
You mean the future, me?
I don't get it. Why would I do that?
Because the method future you told me about isn't one that the you who went to the past was aware of.
Do you understand?
You're saying that for this me right now, there's still a chance I can save Origami?
You got it.
Apparently this isn't over yet.
Let's go!
Indeed.
I agree, it's about time we went ahead and fixed this poor excuse for a world.
Yes.
I'll do literally anything to save her.
That a boy, that's the spirit.
So, how do we do that?
It's pretty simple in theory.
Basically, we're just going to have you try again.
Huh?
What do you mean?
If you think about it, what was the main reason you weren't able to stop Origami?
It was because you had no idea what was about to happen.
Do you see where I'm going?
Yeah, I think I get it now.
Well, the gist is that you're suggesting we use you'd bet on me again, is that right?
An interesting guess, for sure, but I'm afraid that's impossible.
As it stands now, I'm simply sharing your senses.
Or have you forgotten?
I can't physically interact with you in any way.
Then what?
There's another option.
One single method that only I know and can make happen.
Is this the right place?
Oh, absolutely.
Without a doubt.
I don't see anything.
Well, well, lucky me.
I will say, it's definitely not every day that a guest stumbles upon us out here.
Kurumi?
When you know my name right off the bat, that's another story.
Who are you?
And what the hell do you want?
You five years ago?
Yes.
It so happens I was also near the scene when this all occurred.
What the hell were you doing there?
Just checking out what was up with that blaze.
I had the sneaking suspicion that a spirit might be part of an inferno that size.
That makes sense.
So then what you want me to do is...
Yep.
You get to go ask me to shoot you.
With you'd bet.
Listen, I need your help.
You are not to move without my permission.
I can't guarantee you'll survive.
I'm Shido Itsuka.
I came from five years in the future.
And Kurumi, you're the one who sent me.
I swear, if this is some kind of joke...
This is not a joke!
Oh?
Listen!
Please, I need you to listen!
My goodness.
The old Mi sure was a cautious little thing, wasn't she?
Let's try something.
Shido, do you think you could have that Mi physically touch you?
I'll try.
Did you just mumble something?
Kurumi?
Would you come touch my hand?
You can keep the gun on me.
Future Kurumi wants to talk.
Wait, I said that?
Scale of one to ten.
How weird is it if I start with a long time no see?
Very interesting.
You definitely have my voice, so that's a good start.
Want to tell me what this is all about?
I see.
So you're saying all you want me to do is point Yudbet at him and shoot, is that right?
Yes.
I'd say that's precisely what I want.
Very well, then.
Really?
I can't very well refuse myself, can I?
Now, come to me!
Zafkiel!
It appears your time is now!
Zafkiel.
Yudbet.
All right.
Shall we proceed, then?
Yeah.
Orikami, this time it'll work.
I wish you the best of luck, stranger.
Shido.
Oh, Shido.
Looks like it must have worked.
All right, let's change the world.
Can I assume you have some sort of plan, then?
Tick tock.
Time's a-wastin'.
Look, stop pressuring me, okay?
I haven't really had time to think about it.
Remember, you and I both know exactly what's about to happen next.
So I vote you prevent Origami from realizing who killed her parents.
Sound like a good plan to you.
I considered that, too.
But it doesn't address the enormous problem that her parents will still die.
Hmm.
Let's be real.
As long as her parents are killed at the hand of a spirit, any spirit, she can end up directing that grudge towards anyone at all.
On Coterie, who caused the Inferno.
Or Phantom, the one who gave her the power to do that.
What's going on in that head, Shido?
Wouldn't it work out if...
If Origami appeared, but there was no enemy in sight?
Well, yeah, it's possible, but...
Good.
There's something I want to try.
Okay, you do realize you're creeping around like a pervert.
Shut up.
By the way, I assume you know this, but it never hurts to clarify.
You can't interact with Coterie or the others.
Yeah, I get that.
I shouldn't tamper with history any more than necessary.
The only thing I'm here to do is to save Origami.
Shido?
It's here.
Try to refrain, would you?
Coterie, I'm sorry.
Hey!
So you're Phantom.
Been waiting.
You're...
It can't be.
Why are you...
Wait a minute.
How do you know me?
Better hurry.
I'm on it.
Didn't see that reaction coming, did you?
Is that someone you're already acquainted with, Shido?
Nope.
Can't say I know anyone who censors their entire body.
I have to admit, I never would have imagined that your big plan would basically consist of chatting with Phantom.
Is that a problem?
Of course not.
And it's so incredibly like you to attempt that.
But, I can't say it'd be my recommendation.
The fact is, that one is impossible to predict.
Do you know who she is then?
Phantom.
Huh, Phantom, is it?
Am I to understand that's the name I've been given?
I apologize for running off like that before.
I thought it would be better to do this away from her.
Oh, sorry.
Should have done this sooner.
Is that what you look like?
Well, no.
This isn't my real appearance.
I don't think I can show you what I actually look like just yet.
So, do you know who I am or something?
I do.
Very well, yes.
So?
Is that really all you wanted?
You went through the trouble of using a time travel bullet to come back here.
This isn't just a vacation, is it?
How do you know all this?
Fine.
I'll get straight to the point then.
I need you to disappear right now.
Is that your poetic way of saying that you're here to kill me?
No, this is about saving someone.
I just want you to get out of sight.
Fast.
I see.
Sorry, but my answer is no.
I'm afraid that I still have a few things I have to do.
Please, just go.
Origami is about to...
Shido, what's going on?
What's wrong?
Wait.
Why does this feel so familiar?
When the time is right, we should meet again.
I promise you.
This time I'll never let go.
I won't make that same mistake again.
Are you okay, Shido?
Breathe.
Yeah, I'm fine.
Who the heck was she?
Don't tell me.
Origami!
Don't, Origami!
I won't let it.
I can't let that happen to her again.
I will change the past!
Just hold on, okay?
I'm coming!
Origami!
Mom and Dad, there you are.
No Origami!
Doubt!
There's no use.
It's too late.
Dammit!
No, it's not!
Shido, wait!
I did it!
What the...
Wait, wasn't I...
Kurumi?
Kurumi!
Did it work?
Did I do it?
Was I able to save them?
Origami...
And her parents?
Let's make a promise to you and the last one.
No Origami!
傷だらけのままでしないこんでた心
君はそっと拾い上げた
繰り返す日々どうしようもなく紡いだとき
ぎゅっと抱き締めてくれた
I'm always here, you and two of them.
I'll see you next time.
See you next time.